Macklin Underdown

Software Engineer

Detroit, MI (313) 782-2959 macklinu@gmail.com https://mackie.world

SUMMARY

Empathetic, detail-oriented software engineer with 7 years experience of leading and delivering applications across various stacks, primarily with React and TypeScript. Excellent communicator with a focus on written documentation, testing, and mentorship, both in-person and remote.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer • Major League Baseball • San Francisco, CA • SEP 2019 - PRESENT

- Contribute to 8 web apps (React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Mobx, Express, Next.js, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform) and ecosystem of Java microservices for processing, viewing, and editing baseball stat tracking data for both historical and real-time uses.
- Designed and built web application for MLB clubs to share stat tracking data across multiple MLB organizations on time for the 2020 season.
- Incrementally introduced static analysis and unit testing best practices across suite of web applications through examples, mentorship, and pull request reviews.

Front-End Engineer • DIY • San Francisco, CA • APR 2019 - AUG 2019

- Led front-end feature development for diy.org web application and marketing pages (React, TypeScript, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo, CSS-in-JS, Travis CI, AWS) during final four-month phase of merging two products into one.
- Collaborated with backend and mobile engineers to define GraphQL schema updates for new features including multi-step user account migration flow.
- Introduced TypeScript and generated types for GraphQL queries and migrations across 30% of the codebase to improve developer experience and catch potential bugs at compile time.

Front-End Engineer • Crew • San Francisco, CA • MAR 2018 - APR 2019

- Maintained 3 web apps for frontline workplace chat and scheduling, enterprise user management, and internal admin tooling for customer support (JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone, Mustache, LESS).
- Introduced static analysis (ESLint) and process for improving code quality over one-year period.
- Introduced modern web tools (React, Redux, webpack) while maintaining development velocity.

Android and JavaScript Developer • Detroit Labs • Detroit, MI • NOV 2013 - FEB 2018

- Partnered with clients such as Domino's Pizza, General Motors, and DTE Energy to develop and maintain Android apps with 1-5 million downloads and 4+ star app ratings.
- Remotely led front-end web team; built logistics company metrics dashboard product (React, Redux, TypeScript, Node.js, hapi).
- Mentored co-worker in Android development as part of company-wide mentorship program.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan • Ann Arbor, MI • BFA, Media Arts • SEP 2009 - MAY 2013

Wrote, produced, and performed music, created interactive art installations, and developed musical product prototypes. Completed thesis on interactive data visualizations and games, such as real-time Twitter searches or historical stock prices creating dynamic game worlds using Processing.